Finding aid to the Office of the President Thomas Corwin Mendenhall Files. CA.MS.00032
Smith College Archives
- Series IX. COMMITTEES & BOARDS, 2.5 linear feet (6 containers)
  - Administrative Board, 1960-1972; undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Admissions, Board of
    See SeriesV. Administrative Offices-Admissions
  - Aid to Faculty Research and Publication, Committee on, 1960-1970; undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Assistance in Written English, Committee for, 1960-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Audio-Visual Committee
    See Series IV. Administrative Issues-Audio-Visual Facilities & Equipment
  - Campus Planning Committee
    See Series IX. Committees & Boards-College Planning and Resources, Committee on
  - College Planning and Resources, Committee on
    - General, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Budget Study Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Coeducation-General, 1963-1968 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      See the Commitees & Boards series description for other sources of information.
      - General, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - General, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - General, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Alumnae Correspondence, 1969-1973; undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Legal Aspects, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Other Colleges, 1966-1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Questionnaires, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Questionnaires, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Questionnaires, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Reports, OCT 1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Reports, DEC 1969 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Reports, JAN 1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Research Material, 1962-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Subcommittee on Fringe Benefits, 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Subcommittee on Residence Facilities, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Predecessor-College Planning Committee, 1965-1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Predecessor-Faculty Planning Committee, 1959-1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Committees, Committee on, 1959-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Committees, Committee on, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Communications, Committee on, 1969-1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Curriculum, Committee on, 1964; undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Educational Policy, Committee on, 1963-1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Ad Hoc Ctte-"Liberal Arts Education in a Private College", 1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Faculty Conference Committee, 1960-1974 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Faculty Offices, Committee on, 1961-1974 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    see also Series IX. Cttees & Bds-Space Cttee
  - Faculty-Student Committee, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Financial Aid, Committee on, 1966-1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    see also Series V. Admin Offices-Financial Aid
  - Foreign Students, Cttee on, 1968-1974 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    see also Series XVII. Students-International Students
  - Governance, Committee on, 1969-1971 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Honorary Degrees, Committee on, 1959-1974 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    see also Series XI. Events-Hon. Degrees
  - Honors and Independent Programs, Committee on, 1968; 1972 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Lectures, Committee on, 1967; 1974 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Mailing and Duplicating Services at Smith, Committee to Study, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Motion Pictures, Committee on, 1960-1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Physical Education and Recreation, Committee on, 1972-1975 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    see also Series II. Academic Departments-Physical Education
  - Presidential Search Committee, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Review of Research Using Human Subjects, Committee for, 1966-1975 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Science, Committee on, 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Science, Committee on, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Science, Committee on, 1963-1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Smith-Northampton Ad Hoc Committee, 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Social Responsibility, Committee on, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Social Responsibility, Committee on, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Social Responsibility, Committee on, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Social Responsibility, Committee on, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Social Responsibility, Committee on, 1972-1975 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Space Committee, 1959-1969 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    see also Series IX. Committees & Boards-Faculty Offices, Committee on
  - Status of Women and Men, Committee on, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Student Affairs, Committee on, 1965-1967 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Student Affairs, Committee on, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Student Affairs, Committee on, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Student Affairs, Committee on, 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Student Affairs, Committee on, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Student Affairs, Committee on-Minutes, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Student Affairs, Committee on-Committee of Six, 1970-1973 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Student Affairs, Committee on-Faculty House Advisors, 1972-1974 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Student Affairs, Committee on-Security, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Study Abroad, Committee on, 1970-1975 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Tenure and Promotion, Committee on, 1971-1974 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Series X. ENGAGEMENTS, 2.5 linear feet (6 containers)
  This series of records works in concert with the Speeches and Events series to provide a detailed description of the activities and responsibilities of the President of Smith College. Included are a nearly complete set of Mendenhall's appointment calendars (missing only 1968-1969 and 1973-1974), and another set of calendars from the Secretary to the President, Florence McDonald. There is also a large collection of correspondence documenting the planning and organization of Mendenhall's schedule of outside speaking engagements and official functions. The speaking engagements include talks at Smith Clubs, local fraternal and civic organizations, as well as a variety of regional and national organizations. Events which occurred on campus are not documented in this series; that information can be found in the Events series and in the records of specific Smith departments, offices, and committees. The Speeches series includes any notes or transcripts of the speeches given both on campus and off. The records in the Engagements series are organized chronologically by the date of the event.
  - April-December 1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - January-February 1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - March 1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - March 1960-Houston (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - March 1960-Seattle (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - March 1960-St. Louis (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - March 1960-Los Angeles (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - April 1960 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - May 1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - June 1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - September 1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - October 1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - November 1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - January 1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - February 1961 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - March 1961-Dallas (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - March 1961-Tulsa (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - March 1961-New York State (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - April 1961 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - May 1961 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - June 1961 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - September 1961 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - October 1961 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - October 1961-Ohio (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - October 1961-Toronto (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - November 1961 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - December 1961 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - January-February 1962 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - March-April 1962 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - May 1962-Commission on the Status of Women (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - May-June 1962 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - September-October 1962 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - November-December 1962 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - January-February 1963 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - March 1963 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - April 1963 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - June 1963 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - June 1963-Texas (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - October-December 1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - January-February 1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - March-April 1964 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - May-June 1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - September-October 1964 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - November-December 1964 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - January-February 1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - March 1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Richmond, VA, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Atlanta, GA, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Charleston, SC, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - North Carolina, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Birmingham, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - April 1965 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - May-June 1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - July-September 1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - October-November 1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - January-February 1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - March 1966 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Champaign, IL, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Indianapolis, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Louisville, KY, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Ohio, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - April-June 1966 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - October 1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - November-December 1966 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - February-March 1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - April-June 1967 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - July-September 1967 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - October 1967 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - November 1967 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - January 1968 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - March 1968 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Denver, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Seattle, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - April-May 1968 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - June 1968 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - July-August 1968 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - October-November 1968 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - January-February 1969 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - March-April 1969 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - May-July 1969 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - August-September 1969 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - October 1969 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - November 1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - January 1970 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - March-May 1970 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - June-September 1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - October 1970 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - January 1971 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - March 1971 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - April-June 1971 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - October-November 1971 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - February 1972 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - March 1972 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - April-May 1972 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - September-December 1972 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - January-February 1973 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - March-June 1973 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - October 1973 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - January-February 1974 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - March 1974 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Sarasota, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Oklahoma, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Denver, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Dallas, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - May-June 1974 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - October 1974-April 1975, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Calendars-Mendenhall, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Mendenhall, 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Mendenhall, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Mendenhall, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Mendenhall, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Mendenhall, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Mendenhall, 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Mendenhall, 1966-1967 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Mendenhall, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Mendenhall, 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Mendenhall, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Mendenhall, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Mendenhall, 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Mendenhall, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Calendars-McDonald, 1965-1966 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - McDonald, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - McDonald, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - McDonald, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - McDonald, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - McDonald, 1973-1974 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - McDonald, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - McDonald, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Series XI. EVENTS, 2.708 linear feet (7 containers)
  Along with the Speeches and Engagements series, the records in this series document the activities and responsibilities of the President of Smith College. The events in this series (as opposed to the Engagements series) include significant campus traditional gatherings and celebrations as well as one-time happenings. Routine events include assemblies, commencement, Rally Day, and the awarding of Smith College Medals and honorary degrees. Other events include Mendenhall's inauguration, and the college's centennial celebrations in 1974-1975. The centennial records also include research the president did on his own as well as what a paid assistant completed in part for the 1974 Katharine Asher Engel Lecture and its publication as, Chance and Change in Smith College's First Century (Northampton: Smith College, 1976). Documentation of plans to hold an event at Smith in honor of International Women's Year in 1975 are also included in this series, even though the event was eventually canceled.
  - General-Miscellaneous Events, 1960-1975; undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General-President's House Expenses, 1969-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Assemblies/All-College Meetings, 1959-1967; 1973-1975; undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    see also Series XVI. Speeches-Smith Assembly (various dates)
  - Centennial
    - Planning, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Planning, JAN-MAR 1973 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Planning, APR-DEC 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Planning, JAN-APR 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Planning, MAY-JUL 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Planning, AUG 1974- MAY 1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - News Clippings, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Centennial Film, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Centennial Internships, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - TCM's Research on Smith, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      see also Mendenhall's "Chance and Change in Smith College's First Century" (Northampton: Smith College, 1976)
    - Opening Convocation, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Autumn Events, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Winter Program, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "Introducing History"- Mendenhall Symposium, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Centennial Events, 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Oral History Project, 1970-1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Oral History Project, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Oral History Project, 1974-1975; undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Oral History Project-Summary/Excerpts, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Commencement
    - 1960, 1957-1960 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - 1961 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - 1962 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - 1963, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - 1964, 1963-1964 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - 1965, 1964-1965 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - 1966, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - 1967, 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - 1968, 1967-1968 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - 1969, 1968-1969 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - 1970, 1969-1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 1971, 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - 1972, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 1973, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 1974, 1973-1974 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - 1975, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1959-1963 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    See also Series IX. Cttees & Bds-Honorary Degrees,Cttee on
  - Honorary Degrees, 1964-1965 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1970-1975 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Inauguration
    - Program, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Inaugural Address, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Inaugural Address-Correspondence, 1959-1961 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Inaugural Address-News Clippings, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Personal Accounts, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Publicity-Press Releases, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Publicity-News Clippings, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Publicity-Correspondence, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Information for Guests, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Speakers, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Accompanying Events
      - Art Exhibits, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Inaugural Concert, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Folk Concert, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Folk Concert-Ella Fitzgerald, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Luncheon, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Luncheon-Invitation Replies, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Congratulations, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Congratulations-Smith Alumnae, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Congratulations-Colleges and Universities, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Invitations
      - Invitations, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      - Guest Lists, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Guest Lists-Faculty, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Reply Forms, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Replies
        - Honorary Degree Holders, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 24)
        - Board of Counselors, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 25)
        - Pioneer Valley Guests, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 26)
        - Special Guests, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 1)
        - Colleges and Universities, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 2)
        - Government Officials, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 3)
        - Former Trustees, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 4)
        - Emeritus Faculty, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 5)
        - Staff, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 6)
        - Smith Clubs, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 7)
        - Former Faculty and Staff, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 8)
        - Academic Organizations, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 9)
        - Replies-Alumnae, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Inauguration Committee-Correspondence, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Inauguration Committee-Notes-Donald Sheehan?, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Planning
      - Academic Procession, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - Announcements, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - Delegates, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - Financial Records, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Hosts for Guests, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Rain Contingency, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - Registration Lists, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - Sample Invitations, etc. from other Schools, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - Sample Invitations, etc. from other Schools-U of Calif., 1959 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - Seating, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - Staff Instructions, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - Travel and Lodging, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - Ushers, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - International Women's Year, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - International Women's Year, JAN-JUN 1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - International Women's Year, JUL-DEC 1974 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - International Women's Year, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - President's Concert, APR 11, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Rally Day, 1959-1969 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Rally Day, 1970-1975 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Smith College Medals, 1963-1966 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Smith College Medals, 1967-1970 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Smith College Medals, 1971-1975 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Vanderbilt Lecture Series, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Series XII. FACULTY & STAFF, 0.833 linear feet (2 containers)
  The records in this series document the relationship of the President's Office with faculty and staff. There are a number of files for individuals, and two folders of miscellaneous thank-you notes for appointments, salary raises, or other professional occasions. There is also material on a number of general faculty and staff issues, such as housing, internships, salaries, and retirement. Additional material for specific faculty or staff members may be found in the Academic Departments, Administrative Offices, or Committees & Boards the individuals were associated with.
  - General, 1961-1975; undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    see also Series VI. Alumnae-Alumnae Assoc-Faculty Speaking Tours
  - Faculty Club, 1961-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Faculty Housing, 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Faculty Housing, 1966-1974 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Publications, 1959-1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Seminars, 1964-1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    see also Series XIV. Intercollegiate Associations-5 Colleges- Faculty Seminars
  - Faculty Wives Club/Smith Organization of Women, 1959-1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Faculty Workload Experiment, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Individuals
    - Anslow, Gladys, 1960-1961; 1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Arvin, Newton, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      see also Series XVI. Speeches-Smith Assembly (APR 26, 1961)
    - Baskin, Leonard, 1960; 1973 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Bourgoin, Louise, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Cann, Jessie Y., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Carpenter, Esther, 1962-1974 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Carpenter, Russell, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Chase, Mary Ellen, 1960-1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - DeVillafranca, George, 1961; 1970; 1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Dickinson, Alice, 1962-1974 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Dorius, Joel
      See Series XVI. Speeches-Smith Assembly (APR 26, 1961)
    - Drew, Elizabeth, 1961-1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Duckett, Eleanor, 1960-1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Etler, Alvin
      See Series V. Admin. Ofices-Development-Foundations-Mellon
    - Gabel, Leona, 1960-1975; undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Gotwals, Vernon, 1961-1970; undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Greenleaf, Cynthia, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Hanscom, Elizabeth, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Harward, Vernon & Marion, 1967; undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Henderson, Charles, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Heston, Herbert, 1961-1962; 1973; undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Hill, Charles J. and Ruth, 1959-1961; undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Holmes, Vera Brown, 1963; 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Horner, Elizabeth, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Hoyt, Nelly S., 1972; undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Johnson, Margaret, 1962-1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Jones, Peter, 1963; 1971; undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Josephs, Vera, 1965-1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Koffka, Elizabeth, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Lehman, Phyllis, 1963-1972 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - McDonald, Florence, 1968; undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - McElwain, Mary, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - McKay, Ruth, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Marsh, Margaret, 1959; 1966 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Mitchell, Allan, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Morris-Hale, Walter, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Nicholson, Marjorie, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Notestein, Ada Comstock, 1960-1975 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Patch, Howard, 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Petersson, Robert, 1966; undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Pittman, Helen Sinclair, 1966-1972; undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Robertson, Charles, 1960; 1970 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Salvadori, Massimo, 1961-1975 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Scales, Laura, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Schalk, Marshall, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Sheehan, Donald, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Spofford, Edward
    - Unsworth, Richard, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Van der Poel, Priscilla, 1962; 1972 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Von Klemperer, Klemens & Elizabeth, 1960-1968; undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous Thank-you Notes, A-I, 1959-1975; undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Miscellaneous Thank-you Notes, J-Z, 1959-1975; undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Internships-Phillips Foundation, 1962-1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Internships-American Council on Education, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Internships-American Council on Education, 1968-1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Internships-American Council on Education, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Massachusetts Loyalty Oath, 1964-1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Military Deferments, 1963; 1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minority Recruitment, 1967-1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Readers, 1959-1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Retirement/Emeriti, 1959-1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Sabbaticals, 1959-1974 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Salaries, 1959-1963 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Salaries, 1964-1974 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Series XIII. GRADUATE WORK, 1.25 linear feet (3 containers)